- AI's potential to transform your business is vast,
but make no mistake, it introduces new risks
that demand diligent governance.
Don't become another cautionary headline.
Proactively prepare your organization to mitigate AI risk.
In this video, I'll explain why any company
that is serious about leveraging AI technology
needs to prioritize doing an AI risk analysis.
Any promise in technology comes with risks
if not thoughtfully governed.
This is especially true of AI, given the capabilities
and access that the technology increasingly has.
Here's why conducting a risk analysis is essential.
One, it helps identify potential issues
before they escalate, allowing for preventative measures
rather than reactive ones.
Two, it ensures that you meet legal
and regulatory requirements
and reduces the risk of penalties or legal challenges.
Three, it'll help to identify
and mitigate biases or ethical concerns.
This is crucial to maintain trust with your consumers
and upholding your corporate responsibility.
And four, it will ultimately help
identify operational challenges
and contribute to smoother integration
and deployment of your AI technologies.
So how do you go about
actually conducting an AI risk analysis?
First, assemble a team, ideally consisting
of legal, risk management, and technical experts.
Then, start creating a detailed catalog
of AI risk specific to your business.
It's important to involve various stakeholders,
including employees, customers, and external experts
to get diverse perspectives on potential risks.
I recommend that you focus on four key areas,
one, data security, privacy, and permissions,
two, model safety issues,
such as hallucination and harmful content,
three, ethical issues around bias,
transparency, and intellectual property,
and four, legal and regulatory compliance.
For each area, catalog existing controls
and rank the likelihood and impact levels
of incidents if they occur,
then detail specific steps engineering, product,
and legal teams must take to strengthen policies,
monitoring, and responses.
You can leverage established frameworks
like the National Institute of Standards and Technologies,
AI Risk Management Framework,
or Deloitte's Trustworthy AI Framework
to guide your process.
These frameworks offer structured methodologies
for identifying and manage risk
tailored to an organization's unique needs.
Ultimately, recognize that continuous monitoring
and adaptability will be needed.
With AI technologies rapidly evolving
and regulatory landscapes shifting,
it's crucial to regularly update your risk analysis
to stay ahead of new challenges.
Now that you have watched this video,
I encourage you to take some time
to review the NIST's AI Risk Management Framework,
and then proceed to create a robust AI risk management plan.
Remember, the goal is to proactively manage AI risk,
ensuring your AI initiatives are both innovative and safe.
By doing so, you'll be setting your organization
on a path to not just mitigate risk,
but also to leverage AI responsibly and effectively.
Prioritize mitigation planning can help prevent AI failures
or scandals before they emerge.
Don't wait for an incident to happen
before you begin to act.