- As companies unveil
evermore remarkable generative AI
capabilities in the form of new products and services,
it's understandable to be eager
to test the innovative possibilities they present.
I'm the voice in the room telling you to wait.
AI should not drive strategy.
Your business strategy should drive AI implementation.
This means identifying the business problems
and goals first,
then evaluating if and how AI can add value.
Beware of starting a generative AI initiative simply
because it's the hot new thing right now.
Adopting AI technology for technology's sake
rarely delivers value.
The key is to ground your AI initiatives in
practical business needs.
In this video, I'll show you how to identify
and prioritize AI use cases based on real
business goals and challenges.
This will set up impactful
and relevant AI adoption across your organization.
Here's how you can go about doing it.
First, clarify your key organizational objectives.
What business challenges are you facing?
Increased cost pressures,
poor customer retention,
supply chain disruptions.
The goal here is to outline tangible problems.
Next, analyze where inefficiency bottlenecks,
or waste exist in your core operations.
Where could automation
or optimization drive dramatic improvements?
Now using your investment in AI literacy
and increased understanding
of generative AI capabilities and solutions,
which we covered in the previous lesson,
you can begin to brainstorm
how AI can alleviate pain points
or help you capitalize on opportunities.
For instance, if reducing response times
for customer service requests is your priority,
AI powered chatbots might be a helpful solution to explore.
Or perhaps you want a conversational AI assistant
that can improve the closing ratios
of your sales execs by 5%
by providing product expertise in real-time.
The idea is to align AI solutions
to your specific business problems.
You should screen use cases against criteria like
feasibility, business impact, and effort required.
It can also be helpful to categorize use cases into types.
For example, revenue boosting, cost saving,
risk reduction, employee assistance, etc.
The crucial thing to remember is
that not every problem is best solved with AI,
and it's important to evaluate whether the expected return
on investment justifies the resources
and effort needed.
Throughout this process,
be sure to include stakeholders from different functions
to tap into diverse perspectives.
Their insights can reveal opportunities
you might not have considered
and will help ensure that AI solutions resonate
with the people using them.
To put this into practice,
consider hosting brainstorming session with team leaders
to identify pain points that AI could alleviate.
Be sure to stay informed about industry trends
and explore use cases to understand how businesses
similar to yours are utilized in AI.
And more importantly, engage with AI experts
or consultants who can provide an external perspective on
the technical and strategic feasibility
of your AI initiatives.
By focusing on identifying AI use cases
that are closely aligned with your businesses'
challenges and goals,
you ensure that your AI initiatives
are not just technologically sound,
but also strategically valuable.