- Investing in generative AI
is not just about embracing new technology,
it's about driving real business value.
But how do you measure the success of your AI initiatives?
In this video, I'll provide you with a framework
for accurately evaluating your AI solutions performance
and return on investments, including metrics, costs,
and overall business impact.
When evaluating your AI initiatives,
first, revisit the key performance indicators
and milestones that you would've created
during the AI roadmap goal alignment section of this course.
These are your evaluation North Stars.
Assess both quantitative metrics
like usage analytics, and conversions,
and qualitative feedback like surveys
and interviews from staff and customers.
Quantitative data reveals the who, what, and when,
while qualitative data offers the why.
Next, determine comprehensive costs
over your AI solutions full lifecycle.
From research to post-deployment oversight
including maintenance, monitoring upgrades,
and responsible deprecation.
With targets and cost clarified,
you can now begin to calculate business impact.
Intangible terms for example.
If your AI chat bot boosted sales conversion
rates by 7%, you can determine precisely
how much additional revenue that yielded
and compare it against total costs.
This cost benefit analysis determines return on investment,
a metric crucial for executive decision making.
However, traditional ROI calculations focusing solely
on direct financial gains
versus implementation costs don't always apply neatly to AI.
AI impacts include both Hard ROI,
such as direct financial gains like cost savings,
and Soft ROI, broader benefits like employee satisfaction,
decision agility improvements, and future readiness.
You'll need to formulate frameworks to quantify both.
So catalog all measurable cost and time savings,
revenue and productivity lifts as Hard ROI
would also develop indicators
and measures to value software upsides
like skills development, brand enhancement,
and anticipatory capacity.
Stay nimble and reevaluate KPIs
and ROI analyses as markets shift
so you can course correct if needed.
Through accurate evaluation of real world performance
and future strategic impact,
you can justify investments to unlock
AI's last and transformative potential in your business.