- Generative AI is rapidly reshaping business landscapes,
but you can't effectively navigate
what you don't understand.
Yes, companies are over-eager to jump in
and implement this powerful new technology,
but without diligent planning,
attempted AI solutions often fail,
waste resources, or bear unanticipated risk.
Hi, my name is Chris McKay,
and I'm the founder and CEO of Maginative.
Maginative provides AI education and training services
for organizations like yours,
looking to level up and win with new AI technologies.
We have developed a framework for adopting AI
that stitches together business goals,
requirements auditing, solution mapping,
change management, and adoption and iteration
into one coherent strategy.
So if you're ready to learn
how you can strategically adopt generative AI
in your organization,
let's jump in.