- The second phase of our framework Survey
involves conducting a feasibility assessment.
It's about looking closely at your business
and understanding your organization's
current state of AI readiness.
This starts with the technical requirements
of any AI solution that you plan to adopt.
Whether you're using SaaS-based AI products,
fine tuning models on your own infrastructure,
or accessing proprietary ones
like Gemini, Claude, or GBT via an API,
technical requirements are an essential consideration.
In this video, I'll walk you through
how to draft an AI technical requirements document
that outlines the technology and infrastructure needed
to support your generative AI initiatives.
Your AI technical requirements document has twin objectives.
First, it audits current organizational capabilities
related to data, infrastructure, software, et cetera.
And secondly, it defines what is needed to build
or adopt preferred solutions.
In crafting your AI technical requirements document,
here are some elements to review.
Firstly, audit your compute infrastructure.
If you are building a custom solution,
you must decide between running your own models
or using APIs.
Running your models on your own infrastructure
may provide greater control,
but demands comprehensive infrastructure management,
including sophisticated hardware and skilled personnel.
Alternatively, using a managed service or API
will provide access to more advanced models
and allow you to focus on your product development.
Your choice should align with your organization's
needs and capabilities,
balancing both domain expertise with cost efficiency.
Next, recognize that a modern data foundation
is an absolute prerequisite
for effectively leveraging generative AI.
You'll need to catalog
your data sources, quality, and security,
and assess your organization's data availability,
governance policies, and preparedness.
You should also consider how seamlessly your AI solution
integrates with existing systems and their scalability.
As a foundational technology,
you want your AI to evolve alongside your business.
Next, environmental impacts should not be overlooked.
The energy requirements of AI models,
especially when developing your own,
can significantly affect
your organization's carbon footprint.
Be sure to assess this.
Lastly, it's crucial to incorporate
a comprehensive budget estimate
in your AI technical requirements document.
This should include all potential costs
such as licensing fees
for proprietary AI models or software,
and the expenses associated
with infrastructure development or upgrades.
Additionally, consider the ongoing operational costs
such as technical support, data management,
and any necessary staff training or hiring.
In summary, defining the AI technical requirements
is essential for successful implementation and adoption,
whether you're running models on your own infrastructure
or leveraging API-based services.
So I challenge you take some time after this video
and thoroughly document and assess your needs across data,
infrastructure, software, processes, and costs
to ensure your AI initiatives are technically sound
and strategically aligned.
We'll build on this document in the next video.