- Organizing your business
for AI success requires thoughtful leadership
and ownership structures.
I get it,
governance and organizational design isn't exciting,
but it is utterly foundational.
AI solutions live
or die based on operating models wrapped around them.
Here's how you want to think
about approaching structuring AI leadership and ownership
in your business.
First, appoint a dedicated AI leader or group,
ideally someone at the executive level.
Their main responsibilities should include
informing AI strategy, facilitating governance,
managing partnerships, and guide and adoption.
Second, implement cross-functional AI committees
with representatives from business units impacted by AI.
These groups can align on standards, use cases,
risks, and roadmaps.
Importantly, they act as two-way conduits,
disseminating strategy down through the org
and feedback up decision makers.
Depending on the size of your organization,
you can also consider subcommittees focused
on areas like HR, IT infrastructure, finance,
risk, ethics, and compliance.
The more voices represented the better.
Lastly, establish clear AI solution ownership
at the team level where rubber meets the road.
Designate product managers specifically empowered
to drive adoption of new AI tools
or to deliver solutions to customers.
These end-to-end owners can liaise
with technical AI teams on tooling, while also coordinating
with change management for the business users impacted.
Their ownership builds accountability.
Laying this foundation of multi-tiered leadership
and ownership delivers strategic oversight
and direction, while still encouraging agility
through decentralized decision making.
It also fosters learning
and best practice sharing across the organization,
helping to scale AI competency.
Decisive organizational design reduces bottlenecks,
misalignment, and a duplication of efforts
that can otherwise throttle AI success
and value realization.
After watching this video, take some time
to reflect on your current AI governance,
identify any leadership gaps
or unclear ownership that you may need to address
through a proposed organizational redesign.
Remember, thoughtfully design structures empower teams,
maintain alignment to strategy,
and drive accountability for solution success.
In the next video, we'll be looking
at operationalizing your AI strategy, so stay tuned.