- Implementing AI solutions without capable
and enthusiastic employees
and supporters across your organization is a non-starter.
Unfortunately, many leaders discover skill gaps too late,
and this undermines initiatives
after they have already made significant investment.
In this video, I'll demonstrate how
to systematically analyze your talent landscape
to help pinpoint existing capabilities,
identify skill shortages, and inform decisions
on hiring and re-skilling.
All of which are vital for AI success.
So how do we perform an AI skills gap analysis?
Well, it starts
with understanding the specific competencies required
for AI implementation in your business.
This builds on your technical requirements document
that we covered in the previous video.
Start by identifying these roles
and skills across technical, non-technical
and leadership positions.
Then compare these requirements against
your current team's capabilities.
Assess not only their technical skills,
but their readiness to adapt to AI.
Are there team members who
with additional training could fill these roles,
or do you need to consider hiring externally?
Remember, re-skilling your existing team can be as crucial
as hiring new talent.
It's not just about filling gaps,
but also about fostering a culture of continuous learning
and adaptability in the face of technology
that is advancing this quickly.
There are two primary skill gaps that you should focus on.
Those across technical teams that design
and build AI solutions
and those across business teams
that apply AI in their operations.
Technical skill gaps often revolve
around specialized AI tasks, such
as fine tuning models and managing data.
Business skill gaps, on the other hand,
are about understanding AI's role
and capabilities within a business context.
To address these gaps, start by looking internally.
Identify AI thought leaders within your organization
and empower them as AI evangelists.
Focus on retraining and upskilling existing employees,
emphasizing not just technical skills, but also interpretive
and cognitive abilities like creativity
and strategic thinking.
Consider setting up innovation labs
and internal conferences to foster an AI-centric culture
and collaborative learning environment.
If internal resources are insufficient,
you must look externally.
This may involve hiring AI experts,
tapping into young talent through internships,
or partnering with consulting firms
with an experienced talent pool.
Such external hiring should be strategic, focusing on areas
where your organization lacks expertise.
Performing an AI skills gap analysis
and conducting a talent audit are critical steps
towards successful AI adoption.
By understanding and addressing these gaps, you can ensure
that your organization
not only adopts AI technology effectively,
but also remains competitive
in a rapidly evolving digital landscape.