- Well, congrats.
You have reached the end of the course,
and I truly hope it was valuable.
I know that adopting new technology
in a company can be complicated.
This is especially true with AI,
given how fundamentally it changes processes and products.
My hope is that with the usage framework,
I have provided you with a mental model
that you can utilize effectively to guide AI decision making
and equip you with a flexible framework
that you can weave into your existing business strategy.
Feel free to follow me on LinkedIn,
and if you want to learn more about how Maginative
helps companies increase AI literacy across their teams,
you can visit our website.
For now, take care and one love.