- Adopting AI in your organization
is no longer just an option.
It's a necessity for staying competitive and innovative.
In this course, you'll be introduced
to Imaginatives five-step USAGE Framework.
A pragmatic, comprehensive guide
designed for decision-makers like you
looking to strategically adopt AI.
By the end of this video,
you'll understand the framework's components,
and how it helps to align AI initiatives
with your organization's strategic vision.
Navigating the AI landscapes can seem daunting
given how quickly the technology is advancing.
The USAGE Framework breaks down the process
into five intuitive stages:
understand, survey, align, guide, and evaluate.
First, you start by understanding AI through education
and use case identification to set realistic expectations
and build knowledge across your teams.
Next, you survey your business and technology landscape
to audit your readiness.
This feasibility study is essential for scoping requirements
and potential barriers.
Then you align your planned initiatives
to measurable business goals,
crafting an agile roadmap to drive both short
and long-term value.
Next, you guide your rollout through proper governance,
training and an iterative approach to responsible scaling.
And finally, you evaluate performance
through metrics and feedback,
to analyze ROI and determine next phases.
The USAGE Framework simplifies the AI integration journey
into actionable and achievable steps.
It shifts the mindset from reactive to strategic
by ensuring alignment to business priorities early,
and emphasizing practical progression
focused on continuous learning.
In the coming videos,
we'll dive deeper into each of the frameworks components,
and explore practical examples and recommendations
for putting this methodology into practice.
By the end of this course,
you will be able to craft an adoption plan
to integrate AI systematically.
Unlocking more value and building strategic advantage.